The next set of data we'll talk about is related to
下面要讨论的数据
events a company can take that affects its shareholders.
与企业行为有关
This data is called Corporate Actions.
企业行为 即企业能够作出的影响股东的事件
For this lesson, we'll describe only two of the many corporate actions.
企业行为有很多种 在这节课 我们将仅介绍两种企业行为
Stock splits and dividends.
分别是股票分割和股息
Let's start with stock splits.
先看看股票分割
On June 2nd, 1998,
在 1998 年 6 月 2 日
you could buy a share of Amazon for about $85.
你能够以约 85 美元买入一股亚马逊股票
On this date, Amazon decided to perform a two to one stock split.
在这一天 亚马逊决定对股票进行 2:1 分割
Every Amazon shareholder, had their shares doubled.
每个亚马逊股东的股份都翻倍了
This does not mean all of their money in Amazon doubled.
并不是说他们的股票总金额翻倍了
When a stock is split into two,
股票被分割成两份后
its price drops by half.
价格会下跌到一半
This makes sure that the total market capitalization
这样的话 分割后
of a stock has not changed by a split.
股票的总市值不会改变
Market capitalization is the dollar value of a company's outstanding shares.
市值是指企业已发行股票的美元价值
This is calculated by multiplying
计算方法是
the stock price by the total number of shares outstanding.
每股股票的市场价格乘以发行总股数
In this case, there are twice as many outstanding shares.
分割后 亚马逊的发行股数翻倍了
To keep the market capitalization the same,
为了使市值保持不变
the stock price has to drop by half.
股价必须降一半
Why would you ever want to split a stock?
为何要分割股票？
One reason could be to make the stock more liquid.
原因之一是让股票流动性更高
Less expense of stocks are believed to be more liquid.
每股价格越低 流动性越高
Current shareholders and potential investors can now buy and sell and more granularity.
股东和潜在投资者可以更细地调整交易价格
This helps maintain a healthy volume of transactions.
这有助于保持合理的成交量
Amazon later went on to have two more stock splits.
亚马逊之后又两次分割了股票
A three-to-one split on January 5th, 1999.
在 1999 年 1 月 5 日按 3:1 分割
A two-to-one split on September 2nd of the same year.
在 1999 年 9 月 2 日按 2:1 分割
The price dropped to roughly one-third and one-half respectively.
价格分别降到了大约 1/3 和 1/2
I say roughly, because there is still some trading during the day.
我说大约是因为当天依然有一些交易
The closing price ends up being a little different from exactly one-third or one-half,
最后的收盘价与 1/3 或 1/2 稍微有点出入
typically, a little higher due to the renewed interest in the stock.
通常会更高 因为人们重燃了对该股票的感兴趣
If you look at the graph of the stock prices at that time,
观察当时的股价走势图
you'll notice that the large drops are due to the stock splits.
会发现股票分割导致股价大幅下跌
Looking at this graph makes it look like the company dropped in value.
看这个图 好像亚马逊的市值下降了
Using these prices, a computer would read the data the same way.
使用这些价格数据 计算机读取数据后也会得出相同的结论
However, this is not true.
但实际上并非如此
The value of the company has not changed from the split.
企业价值没有因为分割而改变
How do you correct for this?
如何修正这种情况？
One common approach is to normalize the prices to reduce the sudden changes.
一种常见方法是标准化价格 从而降低忽然出现的变化
For instance, you could double the stock price after each two-to-one split,
例如 可以在每次 2:1 分割后使股价翻一倍
triple after each three-to-one split, and so on.
并在每次按 3:1 分割后使估计翻两倍 等等
The trouble with that is,
麻烦的是
your current normalized price will be
标准化后的价格
very different from what the stock is actually trading at.
与股票的实际交易价格差别很大
Instead, we'll do the opposite.
我们将采取相反的措施
We'll have the price before each two-to-one split,
我们将使每次 2:1 分割前的价格变成 1/2
turn it into thirds before any three-to-one split, and so on.
使每次 3:1 分割前的价格变成 1/3 以此类推
Now, the newest adjusted price matches the price currently on the market.
最新调整后的价格与当前的市场价格相符了
Stock prices normalized in this manner is called adjusted price.
以这种方式标准化的价格称为调整价
This is typically provided in most historical data sets.
大多数历史数据集通常会提供这种调整价
Needless to say, you must keep in mind that this is a distortion of reality.
需要注意的是 这与现实不符
In June of 1988,
在 1988 年 6 月
before the first split,
在第一次分割之前
Amazon was not trading at seven dollars.
亚马逊的股价不是 7 美元
It was trading around $85.
而是大约 85 美元
It is the repeated adjustments to historical prices that have reduced 85 to $7.
不断调整历史价格导致从 85 美元降到了 7 美元
With this in mind,
接下来
let's learn about the next corporate action, dividend.
我们将学习另一个企业行为 即股息